大伙儿加油
Let's keep this going, people!
今晚对我们来说非常重要
This is a big night for us.
你  集中精神  用心一些
You! Get it together, man. Focus!
是  主厨
Yes, chef.
21号桌下单  前菜
Table 21. Order in. Appetizer.
一份吞拿鱼  一份猪肚
One tuna crudo. One pork belly.
两份三文鱼  一份乳鸽  一份鹌鹑
Two salmons. One squab. One quail.
不错
Lovely.
上菜
Off it goes.
您的菜
Here you are.
打扰下
Excuse me.
慢用
Enjoy.
各位  愿胃口好
Well, bon appetit, everyone.
埃里克  我再追加两千万
So, Eric, how would another $20 million
投资墨日能源怎么样
for Mexisolar sit with you?
等我参观过工厂后
Once I've seen that factory.
别谈公事了  吃饭  喝酒
Enough business. Eat. Drink.
享受一下人生
Be merry for once in your life.
我的天  这个菜真是美味啊
My god, this food is sublime.
希望如此
I should hope so.
这是全市最难订到位子的餐厅
This is the toughest reservation in the city.
亚瑟
Arthur?
快报警
Someone call 9-1-1.
现在你完蛋了  去死吧
Now you're dead so you can suck it.
还来吗
Oh, you want more?
来啊  哥们
Come get it, buddy.
我为你准备了特殊的大餐
'cause I got something special for you.
我也为你准备了特殊的
And I got something special for you...
大餐
Too.
看起来不太妙啊
Well, that's not lookin' too good.
什么  卡塞尔
What? Castle...
那就勇敢站出来  帕提尔
Well, then stick your head out, Patel,
像个真男人一样受死吧
and get poned like a real man.
谁是帕提尔
Who is patel?
他是一个印度小孩
He's this kid from India.
他已经痛扁我几周了  但今晚别想
He's been thrashing me for weeks, but not tonight.
今晚我的状态非常好
Tonight I am bringing it.
感觉不爽吧  对吗
It stings, doesn't it?
是的
Yeah, it kinda does.
-卡塞尔  -什么事
- Castle. - What?
你宁愿在虚拟世界和小孩子玩
Would you rather play with a kid in an imaginary world
还是和这个
Or with...
在真实世界玩
in the real world.
我
I w--
I, uh, uh...
-我的天  -怎么了
- Oh, my god. - What?
-我的天  你还真的要考虑啊  -不
- Oh, my god. You actually have to think about this? - No.
不  我不用考虑
No. I don't have to think about it.
来吧
Come on over here.
-开什么玩笑  -怎么了
- Are you kidding me? - What?
知道吗  算了
You know what? Forget it.
-真的  为了你我故意死的  -随便
- Seriously, I died on purpose for you. - Whatever.
来嘛  怎么了
Come on. What.
不  她不是我妈
No, I-- it's not my mom.
更糟糕
It's worse.
好  周四碰头
Yeah, see you Thursday.
对不起  你知道我玩游戏时是什么样子
I'm sorry. You know how I get when I'm gaming.
我非常专心  就像格雷茨基一样[冰球运动员]
I was--I was in the zone. I was like Gretzky.
至少人家格雷茨基知道如何得分[得到女人]
Well, at least Gretzky knew how to score.
哎哟  好吧
Ouch. Okay.
再说一遍  我非常非常抱歉
Look, I'm--again, I'm very, very sorry.
你原谅我吗
Do you forgive me?
卡塞尔  就在不久前
You know, Castle, it wasn't too long ago
只要我穿着性感的衣服
when me wearing a sexy outfit would get...
你就会立刻回应
an immediate response from you.
你是说
What are you saying,
你已经视你为理所当然了吗
that I'm taking you for granted?
我不知道  卡塞尔  你是吗
I don't know, Castle. Are you?
两位  被害人在那边
Hey, guys. Victim's over here.
亚瑟·菲尔德  54岁
Name is Arthur Felder, 54.
是个富有的风险投资人
He's a wealthy venture capitalist.
目击证人说他吃了一口乳鸽
Witness said that he took one bite of his squab
就摔在盘子上挂了
and did a nose dive into his plate.
所以说不是过敏反应
Okay, so this was not an allergic reaction?
没有过敏的迹象
There's no sign of anaphylaxis,
但是瞳孔放大以及大量唾液
but his enlarged pupils and excessive saliva
显示食物有异物
suggest a foreign substance.
-他被下毒了  -看起来是这样
- He was poisoned. - It looks that way,
但我在毒检后才能确定
But I won't know for sure until I run a tox screen.
在菜上桌前  有多少人经手
So how many people had access to the food before it was delivered?
埃斯波西托正在调...查
Esposito's checking on that right... now.
那是埃里克·沃恩吗
Is that Eric Vaughn?
对  他和被害人一起吃饭
Uh, yeah. He was part of the victim's dinner party.
-他是亿万发明家  对吗  -对
- He's that billionaire inventor, right? - Yeah.
发明家  创新者  我的LSL单上第八号
Inventor, innovator, and number eight on my L.S.L.
-LSL是什么  -"最后的晚餐"名单
- L.S.L.? - Last supper list.
你和12个人共进晚餐  历史上的任何人都行
You and a table of 12, anyone from history.
你问我的名单上有谁吗  很高兴你问了
What is mine, you ask? I'm glad you did.
排名分别为林肯  爱因斯坦
In order, it is Lincoln, Einstein,
伊恩·弗莱明[007系列作者]
Ian Fleming,
约翰·列侬  圣女贞德
John Lennon, Joan of Arc,
辛纳屈[著名歌手]
Sinatra...
当然有你了
And you, of course.
太迟了  卡塞尔
Too late, Castle.
谁订的位子
So who made the reservation?
我在大约一周前订的
I did, about a week ago.
还有谁知道菲尔德先生今晚会来吗
Did anyone else know that Mr. Felder would be here tonight?
他办公室的人
Uh, his office,
但我不知道他们会告诉谁
but I have no idea who they might have told.
沃恩先生
Uh, Mr. Vaughn?
-好的  -打扰下
- Okay... - Excuse me?
太好了  谢谢  好的
Fantastic. Thank you. All right.
现在是凶案调查
This is a murder investigation.
我需要你集中注意力
I'm gonna need your full attention.
对不起  我在跟我的飞行员通电话
I'm so sorry. That was my pilot.
亚瑟的家人在加勒比海
Arthur's family's in the Caribbean.
我在安排让飞机接他们回来
I was arranging for my plane to bring them home.
你非常慷慨  沃恩先生
Well, that's very generous of you, Mr. Vaughn.
请叫我埃里克  请问你是哪位
No, please, call me Eric. And you are?
我是凯特·贝克特探长
Uh, I'm detective Kate Beckett.
我是理查德·卡塞尔
And I am Richard Castle.
-是那位作家  -是的
- Oh, the writer? - Yeah.
我母亲很喜欢你的小说
My mother loves your novels.
我会送她签名版
Oh, I'll get her an autographed copy.
你跟被害人熟悉吗
So how well did you know our victim?
我们在生意上合作几年了
We'd been doing business for many years.
但恐怕不算熟悉
But, uh, we weren't close, I'm afraid.
知道谁想要他死吗
Any idea who would want him dead?
不知道  这件事太可怕了
None. Uh, this-- this whole thing is terrible.
贝克特
Hey, Beckett.
-抱歉  -没事
- Excuse me. - Of course.
通常情况下  只有少数服务员
So normally only a handful of waitstaff
可能接触到菜  但这次
handle each entree, but in this case,
有可能是外面的人做的
it could've been somebody from the outside.
有一道厨房门强制打开了
There was a kitchen door propped open,
鉴证组发现这件服务员的背心
and C.S.U. found this waiter's vest
藏在垃圾桶里
stashed in a dumpster.
好的  让警员排查这片区域
Okay, have unis canvass the area,
我要盘问所有的厨房人员
And I'm gonna want to interview all of the kitchen staff as well.
好的
Right.
是的
Yes.
怎么
What?
看来沃恩也在你的晚餐名单上
Looks as though Vaughn is on your list as well.
你注意力集中的时候
Oh. The things you notice
很有洞察力呢  卡塞尔
when you're paying attention, Castle.
是的  我在餐馆做了两年
Yeah, I've been a busboy there for two years.
那你8点20的时候在哪
So where were you at 8:20?
8点20  我在后面的洗碗池那边刷碗
8:20? Um, I was at a back sink scraping dishes.
好吧  那你有没有刚好看到
All right. Um, did you happen to see
不认识的人出现在厨房里
anyone in the kitchen that you didn't recognize?
有的  有个人跟我擦身而过
Yeah, you know, someone brushed past me.
我没有看清楚
Uh, I didn't get a good look,
但是我记得他面生
but I remember thinking that he wasn't familiar.
你能描述他的样子吗
Can you describe him?
不确定  他可能是矮个子  深色头发
Not really. He was short, dark hair, maybe.
厨房如战场
Uh, things move fast in the kitchen,
所以我只是眼角瞥到他
so I only caught him out of the corner of my eye.
讲讲后门的情况  一直是开着的吗
Tell me about that back door. Is it always open?
应该是关着的
I-it shouldn't be.
看来受害者  亚瑟·菲尔德
So it looks like our victim -- Arthur Felder--
不是个很和气的人
wasn't the most fuzziest of guys.
他凭恶意收购发了财
He made his fortune in hostile takeovers.
几周前
A couple of weeks ago,
他关闭了一家在纽瓦克的化工厂
he shut down a chemical plant in Newark
分开廉价抛售
and sold it off for parts.
据说两百人因此丢了工作
It says here that 200 people lost their jobs.
据他的助手所说
Yeah, and according to his assistant,
他们宣布倒闭后
they got quite a few death threats
收到了不少恐吓信
after they announced the closing.
恶意收购者关闭化工厂
Corporate raider shutters a chemical plant
最终自食其果  这个案子里  命丧毒鸽
and ends up eating crow, or in this case, poisoned squab.
挺诗意的  虽然很残忍
It's poetic, diabolically speaking.
好的  我和卡塞尔会去找蕾妮
Okay, Castle and I will talk to Lanie
看看毒药和化工厂之间
to see if there's any connection
有什么联系
between the poison and the plant.
同时  你们两个
In the meantime, why don't you guys
去排查一下寄恐吓信的人
go through the list of people that made threats
看看有没有人当时
and see if anyone was in the vicinity
在餐厅附近
of the restaurant?
这就去
Right on.
抱歉  这跟化工厂制造的任何化工产品
Sorry. It's not a match for any of the chemicals
都不匹配
manufactured by that plant.
那他是被什么毒死的
So what was he poisoned with?
某种外来药品  以至于普通和
Something exotic enough not to show up on a chem
罕有毒捡都没查出来
and unknown toxin evaluation.
我在做进一步检测  但我只能肯定
I'm running further tests, but all I can say for sure
这是一种麻痹剂
is that it was some sort of paralyzing agent.
说到麻痹剂
Speaking of paralyzing agent...
我能不能说  埃里克·沃恩啊
Can I just say, Eric Vaughn?!
看到没  卡塞尔
See, Castle?
每个人都想跟他吃饭
Look, he's on everybody's list.
好吧  他的确很出色
Yes, yes, he's quite impressive.
还很帅
And handsome.
别忘了还多金  那个口音
And don't forget rich. And that accent?
-真销魂啊  -我知道
- Ooh, honey. - Oh, I know.
行了  行了
All right! okay.
好吧  我承认
I admit, all right,
正如那些资质一般的人希望成为我
just as lesser men aspire to be me,
他就是那些我这种成功人士也向往的人
he's who the mes of the world aspire to be, okay?
这无法帮我们解决亚瑟·菲尔德的凶案
But that is not gonna help us solve Arthur Felder's murder.
查出他是被什么毒死的才有用
Finding out what he was poisoned with will.
我可以告诉你
Well, I can tell you this,
不管毒剂是什么  都是化学合成的
whatever the poison was, was chemically synthesized
起效非常快
and incredibly fast-acting.
他当时在吃的蘑菇
The mushrooms he was eating
甚至还没进入胃部
never even made it to his stomach.
谢谢  等等  蘑菇
Thank you. Wait. Mushrooms?
我看过菜单
I saw the menu.
蘑菇是跟鹌鹑一起上的  不是乳鸽
The mushrooms were served with the quail, not the squab.
对啊
You're right.
但莱恩说菲尔德吃了乳鸽
But Ryan said that Felder had the squab.
对  这是我的笔迹
Yeah, it's my handwriting.
就在这张小票上
And it's right here on the ticket.
菲尔德点的乳鸽
Mr. Felder ordered the squab.
我们有理由认为
Well, we have reason to believe
他实际上吃了鹌鹑
that he actually ate the quail.
下过毒的鹌鹑  卢卡斯
The poisoned quail, Lucas.
他怎么会吃到的
How did he end up with it?
天呐  肯定是我弄错了
Oh, no. I-I must have made a mistake.
我刚开始学记春季菜单
I'm still learning the spring menu,
鹌鹑炒蘑菇
and the quail with the mushrooms
看上去很像乳鸽炒洋蓟心
looks a lot like the squab with the artichoke hearts.
主厨在大叫
And chef was screaming.
所以你上错了菜
So you mixed up the orders.
天呐
Oh, god.
如果菲尔德点了乳鸽
Okay, if Felder ordered the squab,
那谁点了鹌鹑
then who ordered the quail?
这里写着
Yeah, here it is.
鹌鹑应该是埃里克·沃恩点的
The quail was supposed to go to Eric Vaughn.
菲尔德并不是预计目标
Felder wasn't the intended target.
他们想杀的是沃恩
They were trying to kill Vaughn.
你的意思是  毒是下给我的
You mean to say, that poison was meant for me?
看来是这样
It seems that way.
天呐
Oh, good god.
我该怎么跟亚瑟的妻子交代
What am I gonna tell Arthur's wife?
沃恩先生
Mr. Vaughn--
请叫我埃里克
Eric, please.
埃里克  我理解你的担忧
Eric. Um, look, I understand your concern,
但现在我们要专注于你了
but right now, I think we need to focus on you.
你知不知道有谁希望你死
Now do you know of anyone that would want you dead?
不  但我做到今天的地步必然会树敌
No, but you don't get to where I am without making enemies,
当我的一项发明成功时
when one of my innovations succeeds,
往往表示别人失败了
it often means that someone else's fails.
由于我受人瞩目
And being high profile,
人们往往想从我身上得到点什么
people tend to want things from me
或迁怒于我所不能控制的事情
or get angry for things that I can't control.
看来成为埃里克·沃恩代价不小
Well, it sounds like being Eric Vaughn has its price.
别误会  我不是在抱怨
Don't get me wrong. I'm not complaining.
我敢肯定你每天面对的事情更棘手
I'm sure you face much tougher situations every day.
当有人想杀你的时候
Well, you know, when someone is trying to kill you,
我觉得你完全有权抱怨一下
I think that you have every right to complain.
那最近呢
So what about recently?
有没有收到恐吓
Have you received any threats?
据我所知没有
Not that I'm aware of.
如果我的人觉得事情不严重
But if my people don't think it's serious,
他们可能不会来麻烦我
they often don't bother to tell me.
我助手佩特拉可以提供文件
My assistant Petra can get you the file.
我们需要尽可能多的背景材料
We'll need as much background as she can give us--
心怀不满的雇员  愤怒的竞争对手
disgruntled employees, angry competitors,
诉讼  之类的材料
lawsuits, things like that.
有什么要求尽管提
Uh, whatever you need.
探长
Detective,
凶手仍然逍遥法外
whoever did this is still out there.
认为他们会再次作案并不夸张
It wouldn't be crazy to assume they might try again.
是的
No. Uh, no, it wouldn't.
我可以派些警官来保护你
Um, look, I can assign some uniformed officers to you,
但我想  直到我们找出凶手
but I think, until we figure out who's behind this,
你得考虑雇私人保镖
you might consider hiring private security.
请用
And there you go.
这是什么
What is this?
是我不视你为理所当然的表现
It's just me not taking you for granted.
你和沃恩到底在里面说了什么
So what did you talk about there, you and Vaughn?
我们只是在聊调查的事
Oh, we were just going over the investigation,
讨论接下来的
talking out the next few s--
等一下
Wait a minute. Is this--
你是不是
Are you...
你是在嫉妒吗
Is this you being jealous?
嫉妒
Jealous?
对
Yes.
那家伙赢得了麦克阿瑟天才奖
The guy won a Macarthur Genius Award.
你知道他们把奖颁给什么人吗
Do you know who they give those awards to?
天才们
Geniuses. Okay?
他有一家向非洲运送纯净水的公司
He's got one company bringing clean water to Africa
还有一家或许能治愈癌症的公司
and another one that might actually cure cancer.
所以是的  当你单独和他在房间里时
So, yes, when you're in a room with him alone,
我是有点嫉妒
I'm a little jealous.
我看到你看他的眼神
I saw--I saw how you looked at him.
天呐  卡塞尔  那可是埃里克·沃恩
Oh, my gosh. Castle. It's Eric Vaughn.
他被选为地球上最有趣的
He was voted one of the hundred
一百个人之一
most interesting people on the planet.
我当然会有点激动
Of course I'm gonna swoon a little,
就好像你看到
just like you would
芭儿·拉法莉进屋时一样
if Bar Refaeli walked through the door.
但那毫无意义
But it's meaningless.
你说得对  只是
Yeah, you're right. It's just...
那家伙太吸引人了
The guy's so impressive.
但他不是你
But he's not you.
而且  那家伙能得到他想要的任何女人
Besides, the guy could get any woman he wants.
他对我没兴趣
He's not interested in me.
可不是嘛
Right? I know.
好了
Okay.
我和委员谈过
I spoke with the commissioner,
他同意为沃恩提供保护
And he's agreed to provide Vaughn with a protective detail.
很好  我可以为他推荐
Uh, great. I actually have a few uniforms
几个警员
that I'd like to recommend for duty.
不  沃恩先生指定要你
No. Mr. Vaughn has requested you.
他要干嘛
He what now?
长官  我是凶杀案探长  不是保镖
Sir, I'm a homicide detective, not some bodyguard.
相信我  我知道
Trust me, I know.
但这是委员直接任命的
But this comes directly from the commissioner.
为什么沃恩不直接雇一支私人军队呢
Why doesn't Vaughn just hire a private army?
他承担得起
He can afford that.
我不知道为什么  卡塞尔先生
I don't know why, Mr. Castle.
我只知道我的任务是什么
I just know what my orders are.
他要贝克特探长  而且只要贝克特
He wants detective Beckett and only Beckett.
他能那么干吗
Can he even do that?
我想他已经那么干了
I think he just did.
贝克特和沃恩在一起
Beckett's hanging with Vaughn?
那你当然得担心了
Oh, hell, yeah, you should be worried.
他在"最性感一百人"榜上有名
His hit list includes half of "Maxim's" Hot 100.
而且跟你不同的是
Oh, and unlike you,
他的直升机可不用遥控
His helicopter doesn't need a remote control.
别听他的  卡塞尔  贝克特对你忠贞不二
Don't listen to him, Castle. Beckett's loyal to you.
她不会被他的魅力所勾引
She's not gonna be seduced by his charms.
真的吗  你会让珍妮跟他出门吗
Really? So you'd let Jenny hang with him then?
不可能  我不会让珍妮靠近那家伙
Hell, no. I wouldn't let Jenny near that guy.
多谢
Thanks.
好吧  但是我不担心
Okay, but... I'm not worried.
我不担心好吗  我只是
I'm not. Okay? I just--
我不相信局里会违背她的意愿
I can't believe that the department
让她和一个风流倜傥的有钱人
is forcing her to hang out with some womanizing rich guy
一起出去
against her will.
是的  不可思议
Yeah. Unbelievable.
是啊  这可前所未有
Yeah, she's never done that.
你们知道我们该怎么办吗
You know what we need to do?
我们必须尽快解决这个案子
We need to solve this case, and fast.
好吗  我们越早抓到凶手
Okay? The sooner we catch this killer,
就越早让她远离沃恩
The sooner we get her away from Vaughn.
在巷子里找到的服务员背心进展如何
Where are we on that waiter vest we found in the alley?
鉴证组检查了痕迹证据  没有纤维
C.S.U. was checking for trace evidence. No fibers.
而且也没能从扣子上提取指纹
And they couldn't pull any prints off the buttons.
不行  让他们再做一次
No. Have 'em do it again.
穿着那件背心的就是凶手
Whoever wore that vest is our killer.
-我知道  我们以前干过  -是吗
- I know. We have done this before. - Have you?
卡塞尔  淡定
Castle! Chill.
我们有其他线索
We may have another lead.
警员在发现那件背心的
Uniforms picked up a homeless guy
巷子里抓到一个流浪汉
in the same alley right where that vest was found.
他可能看到了一些东西
He may have seen something.
好吧  那怎么不去审问他
Well, then why aren't we talking to him?
因为现在他正醉着呢  看东西都重影
Because at the moment, he is stupid drunk. Seeing double.
等他醒了也许能更好地描述事实
We'll have a better chance of a description once he sobers up.
-交给我了  -什么叫交给你了
- I'm on it. - What do you mean, you're on it?
-你去哪  -去给他
- Where are you going? - To make
弄一杯他喝过的最提神的咖啡
him the best damn cup of coffee he's ever had.
这是个大错误
This is a big mistake.
让我保住你性命最好的方式
The best way for me to keep you alive
就是出去破案然后抓住那个幕后黑手
is to get out there and catch the guy that's behind this.
你低估自己了  探长
You underestimate yourself, detective.
我确定你能两者兼顾
I'm quite sure you can do both.
你愿意拿自己的命来赌吗
And are you willing to bet your life on that?
你根本不认识我
You don't even know me.
我了解得够多
I know enough.
你作为优等生毕业
You graduated at the top of your class.
你是纽约警察局历史上
You're the youngest woman
最年轻的的女探长
in the history of the NYPD to make detective.
你比局里的任何人
You have the highest closure rate
结案率都要高
of anyone in the department.
今年早些时候
And earlier this year,
你打破规章救了一位议员的命
you bucked every protocol to save a senator's life.
你知道你有多优秀吗
Do you have any idea how remarkable you are?
你不知道  对吧
You don't, do you?
如果有谁能保护我  那就是你
If anyone can keep me safe, it's you.
下午好  埃里克
Good afternoon, Eric.
我们已经加强了安保
We've put extra security in place,
但我们得谈谈墨日能源的事
but we have to talk about Mexisolar.
这是贝克特探长
Detective Beckett,
这是大卫·安德森  我的律师
David Anderson, my attorney.
探长在保护我的安全
The detective is looking after me,
所以确保她能得到她需要的一切
so make sure she has everything she needs.
如果他给你添麻烦
If he gives you any trouble,
我们可以让他去开一整天投资会议
we can put him on investor conference calls all day.
我或许会接受这个提议
I might take you up on that.
埃里克  如果我们想让Q-3顺利发行
Eric, it's important to keep Mexisolar R&D moving
-就得保持墨日能源研发部保持运作  -探长
- if we want to launch Q-3. - Detective.
我按你的要求整理了我们
I put together summaries of our entire portfolio
所有公司的卷宗
of companies per your request,
还有对他们或沃恩先生的所有投诉
along with any complaints against them or Mr. Vaughn.
一小时后向你报告
Briefing in an hour?
那太好了  谢谢
Yeah, that would be great. Thanks.
蕾妮  什么事
Hey, Lanie. What's up?
你要的死因
Your cause of death.
毒药是化学合成的
The poison was a chemically synthesized,
武器化制剂
weaponized agent,
类似于蛤蚌毒素的有机化合物
similar to the organic compound saxitoxin.
蛤蚌毒素
Saxitoxin?
通常出现在贝类食物里  但不是这样的
It usually occurs in shellfish, but not this version.
制毒的人肯定能进入精密的实验室
Whoever created this had access to a pretty sophisticated lab,
而且这毒是加强的
and this one's been supercharged.
说到精力过人
Speaking of supercharged,
你真的和埃里克·沃恩在一起吗
Is it true that you're with Eric Vaughn?
凯特  我知道你爱卡塞尔
I mean, Kate I know you love Castle and all,
但是  亲爱的
but, girlfriend--
再见  蕾妮
Bye, Lanie.
再见
Bye.
你好  蕾妮
Hello there, Lanie.
我是埃里克·沃恩.
I'm Eric Vaughn.
我觉得你真是让人销魂
Ah, and I think you're absolutely ravishing.
蛤蚌毒素
Saxitoxin?
对  你有了解吗
Yeah, are you familiar with it?
沃恩集团和一所大学的实验室
The Vaughn Alliance partnered with a university lab
合作开发针对那一族神经毒素的
to develop a next-generation antidote
新一代解毒剂
to that entire class of neurotoxins.
你和实验室有关的哪个人有纠纷吗
And have you had troubles with anyone associated with the lab?
辛迪
Cindy.
辛迪是谁
Who's Cindy?
辛迪·帕拉蒂  她是我们的首席研究员
Cindy Paralti. She's our lead researcher.
几个月前
A few months ago,
我们去出席新加坡的一场会议
we were presenting at a conference in Singapore.
我们喝了几杯  然后...
We had a few drinks, and--
结果弄得很难堪  我懂
And it ended badly. I get it.
事实上  开头就不妙
Actually, it started badly.
她向我表达了深厚的爱意
She expressed some deep-seated feelings for me,
可我对她没意思
ones that I didn't share,
所以我拒绝了她  她很难接受
so when I declined, she took it hard.
他一直有礼有节
He is being polite.
她玩了几周《致命诱惑》
She went "Fatal attraction" for a couple of weeks.
这样你还和她继续共事
And you still work with her?
她是个很有才能的研究员
She's a very talented researcher.
警探  我们都有被内心误导的时候
Detective, we're all misled by our hearts sometimes.
这不该断送职业生涯
It shouldn't end a career.
也不该葬送生命
It shouldn't end a life, either.
辛迪住在哪里
So where does Cindy live?
在曼哈顿下城区的高校实验室附近
By the university labs in lower Manhattan.
住在市里  餐馆附近
So in the city... near the restaurant.
还能拿到蛤蚌毒素
And with access to saxitoxin.
我有麻省理工的化学博士学位
I have a PhD in chemistry from M.I.T.
当然听说过蛤蚌毒素
Of course I've heard of saxitoxin.
相当危险的东西  辛迪
Pretty dangerous stuff, Cindy.
你工作中用到过吗
You ever work with any of it?
用到过  很多其它实验室也用过
We do, as do a lot of other labs.
帕拉蒂女士  我们知道你和埃里克·沃恩
Ms. Paralti, we understand that you and Eric Vaughn
私下翻脸了
had a personal falling out.
是啊  怎么了
Yeah. So?
有不开心吗
So any hard feelings?
很痛苦  不过我想开了
It was painful, but I got over it.
是吗  那可不是你的作风
Did you? Because that hasn't been your pattern.
你的三位前男友都对你申请了限制令
You've had restraining orders filed against you by three ex-boyfriends.
你刮花了他们的车  划破了轮胎
You've keyed cars, slashed tires.
活脱脱演绎了凯莉·安德伍德的歌
Straight out of a Carrie Underwood song.
对  可你知道吗
Yeah, but you know what
-凯莉·安德伍德没唱过什么吗  -什么
- Carrie Underwood never sang about? - What's that?
用强效神经毒素
Using a chemically enhanced neurotoxin
在餐馆毒死人
to poison a guy in a restaurant.
你看  埃里克·沃恩逃过一劫
See, Eric Vaughn, he survived.
可有个人却没那么幸运
But one of the other people he was with wasn't so lucky.
有人想杀埃里克
Someone tried to kill Eric?
不  我绝不会杀他
No. I would never.
帕拉蒂女士
Ms. Paralti,
你能接触到毒素
you had access to the toxin.
你昨晚在哪里  辛迪
Where were you last night, Cindy?
在歌剧院  看《蝴蝶夫人》
At the opera. "Madame butterfly."
你们可以去查
You can check.
我有发现
I got something.
好了  喝了两杯咖啡  一杯拿铁
Okay, so after two cups of coffee, a latte,
三杯浓缩咖啡后  我们这位流浪汉朋友
and three espressos, our homeless friend--
坐在那边的黑泽顿先生  终于清醒了
Mr. Hazelton over there-- finally sobered up.
他说看到是谁往垃圾桶里扔的背心了
He said he saw who stashed the vest in the dumpster.
他说那家伙穿着餐馆工作服
He said the fellow was dressed in a busboy uniform.
等等
Wait a minute.
你说说不是外人干的
Are you saying it wasn't someone from the outside?
是伊爱阁的工作人员干的
It was someone who worked at Iago?
对  于是我给他看了几张伊爱阁雇员的照片
Right. So I showed him photos of all the Iago employees,
他指认出这个人
And he fingered this guy.
科瑞·哈里森
Cory Harrison.
等等  我和这人说过话
Wait a second. I spoke with this guy.
他试图归咎于另一个人
He tried to pin it on somebody else.
那他就是在撒谎  试图制造出
Well, then he's lying, trying to make it look like
是外人干的假象  贼喊捉贼
it was someone from the outside when it was him all along.
-他为什么要毒害沃恩  -一问便知
- Why would he want to poison Vaughn? - Let's ask him.
-要咖啡吗  -不要
- Coffee? - No.
我或许也该停了
I should probably stop, too.
再来一杯
One more.
纽约警察
NYPD!
警察
Police!
来这边
Over here.
看来有人先到了一步
Looks like someone got here first.
鹅绒过敏吗
Ooh. Goose down allergy?
我没事的  科瑞·哈里森就不行了
I'll live, unlike Cory Harrison.
凶手显然用枕头充当了静音器
Killer clearly used a pillow as a poor-man's silencer.
也没有强行入室的迹象
No sign of forced entry, either.
或许他认识凶手
Maybe he knew his killer.
而且他有心理准备了
He also knew what was coming.
哈里森先生的手腕上有防卫伤
I found defensive wounds on Mr. Harrison's wrists.
不过我找不到别的了
But that's all I'm gonna find.
有人用漂白剂清洗了他的双手
Someone washed his hands with bleach.
处理掉DNA和痕量证据
Disposing of D.N.A. and trace evidence?
看来凶手是个职业杀手
Shooter sounds like a pro.
对  我想我知道他来这里的原因
Yep, and I think I know why he was here.
实验室证实了
The lab confirms it.
科瑞·哈里森公寓里的瓶子
The bottle in Cory Harrison's apartment
含有杀死菲尔德的毒素
contains the toxin that killed Felder.
所以是有人借刀杀人
So someone was using him to spike Vaughn's food,
然后过河拆桥
and then got rid of him.
所以哈里森的生活中
Which means somewhere in Harrison's life--
家庭  财务  或工作中
His family, financials, or work--
有找到幕后主使的关键
There's the key to whoever's behind all of this.
或许餐馆有人知道他的事
Maybe someone at the restaurant knew what he was up to.
我们该回去问问
We should go back there. Mm-hmm.
不  你和其他警探可以回去调查  卡塞尔先生
No, you and the boys can go back there, Mr. Castle.
贝克特得去法维克酒店
Beckett's going to the Fairwyck Hotel.
法维克里有什么
What's at the Fairwyck?
埃里克·沃恩
Eric Vaughn.
只要凶手还没落网
As long as we have a killer running around,
就得保证他待在安全的地方
I need him somewhere safe.
他定了总统套房
So, he booked the presidential suite,
从现在起  直到我们找到幕后真凶
and from now until the time we catch whoever's behind all this,
你都得和他待在一起
you're staying there with him.
在总统套房
In the presidential suite?
长官  你没开玩笑吧
Uh, sir, are you s-serious?
你想让我照看他
You want me to babysit this guy?
他坚持这样
He's insisting.
显然  你让他赞不绝口
Apparently, you made quite an impression.
长官  我...
Uh, sir, I--
警探  我知道你有所顾虑
Detective, I know how you feel,
可杀了那个餐馆工的人是个职业杀手
but whoever killed that busboy was a pro,
所以他可能卷土重来
which means he may strike again,
我不能让世上最有影响力的人之一
and I am not going to lose one of the world's most influential men
在我眼皮底下遇害
on my watch.
保驾护航是一回事
You know, it's one thing to follow him around,
和他同居又是一回事
but quite another to be shacking up with him.
卡塞尔  我不是要和他同居
Castle, I am not shacking up with him.
我只是在尽我的职责
I'm just doing my job.
是啊
Right.
你不相信我
You don't trust me.
我当然相信你
Oh, no. Of course I trust you.
你才不信  所以你才这个样子
No, you don't. That's what this is all about.
不然的话  我们根本不用讨论这件事
Otherwise, this wouldn't be an issue.
可以走了吗
Shall we?
当然
Yes.
这种时候还有心情喝咖啡
A coffee break at a time like this?
没搞错吧
Really, guys?
你怎么了  兄弟
What's your problem, bro?
你快给珍妮打电话
Look, you need to call Jenny,
你该打给谁就打给谁
and you need to call whoever it is you call,
因为只要案子没破  我们就都不会回家
because we are not going home until we solve this murder.
听到了吗
All right?
现在咱们去餐厅找找答案
Let's get to that restaurant and get some answers.
我没有开玩笑
Seriously, guys. I mean it.
这是我见过最棒的安全屋了
This is the nicest safe house I've ever seen.
既然有人想要你的命
Well, if someone's trying to kill you,
不如把担惊受怕的生活过得舒坦点
you might as well make the most of it, eh?
我该开始工作了
I should get to work.
帮我给诺瓦公司道歉
Apologies to Novatech,
去墨日能源的行程也推到夏天吧
and let's cancel the Mexisolar trip until summer.
谢了  佩特拉
Thanks, Petra.
你最后一次联络杰夫·萨斯曼是什么时候
When were you last in contact with Jeff Sussman?
不是萨斯曼干的
It's not Sussman.
但是你开除了他
But you fired him,
他还挪用公款
and he was convicted of embezzling.
对我来说这就是犯罪动机
That sounds like a suspect to me.
他办砸了事  不过也付出了代价
Look, the guy screwed up and paid for it.
但我把他妈妈安排进养老院
But I set his mother up in an assisted-living facility.
杰夫很感激
Jeff was very grateful.
不是他
It's not him.
你约了人吗
Are you expecting anyone?
我冒昧地叫了客房服务
I took the liberty of ordering some room service.
晚上好  女士  我可以进去吗
Good evening, ma'am. May I come in?
抱歉  不行
Uh, actually, no. Sorry.
考虑到菲尔德被杀害的方式
Listen, given the way that Felder was killed,
我想让我们的人监督食物的准备过程
I would prefer if my people oversaw the food preparation.
我可不可以拿香槟进来
May I at least grab the champagne?
它是密封的
It is sealed.
好  你拿吧
Yeah. Okay, fine.
不好意思
Excuse me.
给
Here.
谢谢  先生
Thank you, sir.
我会安排人送吃的
I'll make sure that we get you some food up here.
没关系  最重要的我们已经有了
That's okay. We have the essentials.
帮你倒一杯
Pour you a glass?
不  谢了  我在执勤
Oh, no, thank you. I'm on duty.
你对工作很认真
You take your work seriously.
我喜欢你这一点
I like that about you.
让我觉得很安全
It makes me feel safe.
我的天啊
oh, my God!
你还好吗
Are you okay?
没事  我觉得你得防着我害死自己了
Yes. I think you're gonna have to protect me from myself.
我去帮你拿点冰块
Okay. Um, I'm gonna go and get you some ice, okay?
你知道吗  我很高兴科瑞死了
You know what? I'm glad Cory's dead.
那件事之后
After what happened,
该死的卫生部就不让我们营业了
the bloody health department shut me down.
如果我知道他干了什么  我也会亲手杀了他
I mean, if I'd known what he did, I'd have killed him myself.
不过我们认为
Yeah, except we think
让他在你餐厅里投毒的人
whoever put him up to poisoning your food
就是杀了他的那个人
was the one who killed him.
你想报仇吗  帮我们找到凶手
You want revenge? Help us find his killer.
你想知道什么
What do you want to know?
投毒那天你有没有发现科瑞
Did you notice anything unusual about Cory
有反常的举动
the day of the poisoning?
那个混蛋迟到了
Yeah. The son of a bitch was late.
抱歉  这就算反常了
I'm sorry. That's it?
你不明白  从来没人迟到
You don't understand. No one's late, ever.
这是我的规矩
It's one of my rules.
我就应该当场开除他
I mean, I should've fired him on the spot.
为什么没有呢
Why didn't you?
因为他的眼神
The look in his eyes.
就像见了鬼一样
It was like he'd seen a ghost.
那天他绝对出了什么事
Something happened to him that day.
坏事
Something bad.
来
Here.
可以消肿
That should help with the swelling.
是啊  但伤了的自尊是回不来了
Yes, but, uh, not my pride.
你有这样的"手法"
You know, with your bedside manner,
你真该去当医生
you could've been a doctor.
我吗  不行
Me? No, no.
律师有可能  我读过法学预科
A lawyer, maybe. I was, uh, in pre-law.
在你状告酒塞的案子上
I could've represented you
我本可以当你的辩护律师
in your case against the cork.
但是你却当了警察
But instead, you became a cop.
为什么
Why?
一个跟我很亲近的人被杀害了
Uh, someone close to me was killed,
这...
and that just...
改变了一些事  也改变了我
changed things and changed me.
我本来想当个建筑师的
You know, I was supposed to be an architect.
没开玩笑
No, seriously.
但在我上大学的时候我姐姐去世了
But my sister died when I was in college--
先天性心脏病
heart defect.
所以我辍学
So I dropped out
发明了一种新的人工心瓣
and invented a new heart valve.
那是我第一项专利
That was my first patent.
这样被命运改变了生活可真神奇  对吗
It's amazing how fate changes lives, isn't it?
我要回去工作了
I should get back to work.
至少喝一杯吧
At least have a glass of champagne.
毕竟我可为它受了苦头
I mean, I have suffered for it, after all.
好吧
Okay, fine.
既然你这么说了
You know what? You put it that way...
就半杯吧  行吗
but just half a glass, okay?
再多一点  大半杯
Go on. Three-quarters.
好吧
Yeah.
我们找过科瑞·哈里森的女朋友
We talked to Cory Harrison's girlfriend.
据她说  昨天早上他离开她家时
According to her, he was in a good mood
心情很不错
when he left her apartment yesterday morning.
那肯定是在去餐厅的路上
Then something must have happened
发生了一些事
between home and the restaurant.
事实上  的确是这样
In fact, something did.
我们查了科瑞的行程
We took a look at Cory's routine.
基本每天早上他离开家之后
Pretty much every morning, he left his apartment,
送他女儿去幼儿园
picked up his daughter, took her to preschool.
步行去公交车站
Then he'd walk to the bus stop,
坐10-x公交车
where he'd catch the 10-x
从斯塔顿岛去市里
from Staten Island into the city.
太好了  警监  你来了  告诉她了吗
Ah. Great, captain, you're here. Did you tell her?
告诉了
I did tell her.
这是昨天公交车站的
Okay, this is the security video footage
安保监控录像
from the bus shelter yesterday.
给她看看
Show her the...
谢谢
Thank you.
科瑞  就是那个服务员在和别人说话
There's our busboy Cory talking to some guy.
这辆车是10-x公交车
And that is the 10-x bus,
但是科瑞却没上去
but Cory does not get on.
他都要迟到了
He is late for work.
却顶着被开除的风险继续和那个男的说话
He risks getting fired just to talk to this guy.
对这个人  我们有什么了解
Well, what do we know about him?
一无所知  看不清他的脸
Nothing. We can't get a good look at him.
他好像知道摄像头在哪里
It's like he knows where the camera is.
对  不过从这里就开始有趣了
Right, but this is where it gets interesting.
-我该怎么  -那个键
- How do I... - That one.
按这个吗
That one?
慢着  那就是毒药
Wait. That's the bottle of poison.
没错  而且在他下毒之后
Right, and after he used it to poison the food,
我认为是这家伙开枪打死了他
I'm betting this guy came back and shot him
以绝后患
to tie up loose ends.
这人就是凶手
He's your killer.
我也希望能帮上忙
Look, I wish I could help you,
可是我真不认得这人
but, uh, I simply just don't know him.
莱恩  我们得把录像再研究一遍
Ryan, we gotta go over that video again.
肯定会有线索能让我们查出
There's gotta be something in it that'll help us figure out
这人是谁
who he is.
失陪一下
Uh, excuse me.
看来你俩挺享受啊
Looks as though you two were enjoying yourselves.
卡塞尔
Castle--
穿什么睡衣呢
What about pajamas--
家居服还是性感睡衣
Homely flannel or skimpy sleep shorts?
天呐  你说话跟我爸送我去夏令营时
Oh, my gosh. You're sounding like my dad
一模一样
dropping me off at summer camp.
夏令营有香槟喝吗
Did they serve champagne at your summer camp?
人家盛情难却
I was being polite.
卡塞尔  你以为我喜欢这样吗
Castle, do you think I want this?
你以为是我要求来这来的吗
Do you think I asked to be here?
我觉得你挺享受的
I think you're making the best of it.
你知道我情愿和你一起
You know I would rather be with you.
那要不我留下吧
Well, then maybe I should stay
咱俩一起保护他
and we can protect him together.
不行  我不准
No, I am not letting you do this.
我不会让你把调查案子
I'm not letting you turn this investigation
变成一场扭曲的爷们比拼
into some kind of a twisted competition.
听话
Look...
别添乱子了
Don't make this harder than it needs to be.
-求你了  -好吧
- Please. - Okay.
既然你都求我了
But only because you said please.
既然我们没法看清他的脸
Since we can't get a clean look at this guy's face,
我希望有别的办法
I'm hoping there's some other way
能查明他的身份
we might be able to I.D. Him.
幸运的是  除了脸
Fortunately, we're all much more
我们还有很多特征
than our faces, detective.
哈里森的驾照上说他身高1米76
Harrison's driver's license lists him at 5'10".
另一人看起来身高1米85
That other guy looks like he's 6'2".
从站立姿势能看出他的脊椎弯曲度
Posture is an indication of spine curvature.
依此看  我估计他40岁出头
I'd say it puts him in his early 40s.
注意他的手
Watch his hand.
他做了两个特别的动作
He makes two distinct movements.
他先是抓住哈里森先生的手臂
First he grabs Mr. Harrison's arm,
然后他把毒药交给了他
then he passes him the poison spray.
他是个左撇子
He's left-handed.
再留意他的脖子
And look at his neck.
是块创可贴
That's a bandage.
也许是最近弄伤了
Maybe covering up a recent injury
或是掩盖纹身
or a tattoo.
-对  -嘿
- Yeah. - Hey.
我知道这家伙是怎么
So I think I know how this guy
让科瑞帮他下毒的了
got Cory to poison the food.
别告诉我是因为钱  我看过他的财务状况
Don't say money. I've been through his financials.
他不缺钱
There's nothing there.
可能是让他更难以拒绝的方式
Might be something a lot more personal.
我去调查了科瑞女儿上学的幼儿园
I canvassed the preschool that Cory's daughter attends.
我展示了录像截图
A teacher recognized him
一个老师认出了他
when I showed her the screengrab.
在凶案前一天
Remembers seeing him
她发现他在学校附近出现
hanging around the school the day before.
所以你觉得他拿科瑞的女儿来威胁他
So you think he threatened to hurt the daughter
逼他去下毒
if Cory didn't poison the food?
这也许解释了  他去上班时
It might explain why he was so upset
为何忧心忡忡的
when he got to the restaurant.
弹道检测得怎样了
Where are we on ballistics?
现场发现的弹头严重损毁了
Slug from the crime scene is pretty mangled,
但在数据库里有可能找得到匹配纪录
but it's a possible match to another one in the system.
过几个小时应该就有结果了
We should know more in a few hours.
好啦  爸
Okay, dad.
包装盒上说
The box said something about
本饮品含安神压惊的草药成分
a soothing infusion of calming herbs.
反正  这是安神茶  你得安安神
Anyway, it's a calm tea, and you need to calm down.
我怎么安得下来啊
How am I supposed to calm down?
他可是埃里克·沃恩
It's Eric Vaughn.
爸  贝克特那么喜欢你
Dad, Beckett is over the moon for you.
你就信任她一下嘛
So give her a little credit, huh?
这就跟她当年保护参议员布莱肯一样
It's no different than when she was protecting Senator Bracken.
是啊  你说得对
Yeah, you're right.
不过她保护布莱肯时
Oh! Except for the fact that when it was Bracken,
他们可没搞睡衣派对
they weren't having a slumber party
也没住豪华酒店
at a fancy hotel.
接受现实吧
And let's face it.
跟布莱肯一比
Compared to Bracken,
埃里克·沃恩帅得像乔治·克鲁尼一样
Eric Vaughn is like George Clooney.
才怪
Oh, no.
埃里克·沃恩比克鲁尼帅多了
Eric Vaughn's way sexier than Clooney.
本来就是嘛
What? He is.
没错  而贝克特正在高级套房保护他呢
Yes, and Beckett is protecting him at the Fairwyck as we speak.
哎妈呀
Oops.
我正在劝老爸  贝克特是个职业化的警察
I was just reminding dad that Beckett is a professional
而且对他一心一意
and totally committed to their relationship.
这个嘛
Eh, well...
说不上一心一意
Not totally committed.
什么意思
What do you mean?
她手指上没戴戒指  对吧
Well, there isn't a ring on her finger, is there?
-我  -按理说  她不完全一心一意
- I... - Technically, she's not really committed at all.
拜
Ta.
再给我来点安神茶
I'm gonna need more of that tea.
贝克特  弹道检测发现匹配记录
Hey, Beckett, ballistics got multiple matches
射杀科瑞·哈里森的那把枪
on the gun used in Cory Harrison's murder,
在纽约州外
connecting the weapon
还犯过四起凶案
to four killings outside the state.
好  那几起案件发生在哪儿
Okay, so where were those other murders?
底特律  芝加哥  拉斯维加斯和孟菲斯
Detroit, chicago, Las vegas, and Memphis.
这些案证据不足  但查到了一名嫌犯
There was never enough evidence, but a name did come up.
-谁  -托马斯·巴伯
- Who? - Thomas Barber.
42岁  之前做过黑帮小弟
42. Used to be a button man with links
跟芝加哥有组织犯罪团体有联系
to organized crime in Chicago.
根据他的档案  他现在是个自由职业者
According to his file, he's a freelancer now.
我把他的照片发给你
I'll text you his photo.
那他就是公交站监控录像里的那个人吗
So is this the same guy that we saw on the bus stop video?
是的  身高年龄都一致
Yep. He's a match for height, age,
-脖子上有一块恐怖的纹身  -好的
- And placement of a creepy neck tattoo. - All right.
全面通缉他
Put an A.P.B. out for him
开始排查飞机和火车的旅客名单
And start checking plane and train manifests,
其他进城的交通系统也要监控
along with any other transportation systems
另外  要小心
into the city, and keep in mind,
这人是职业杀手  只要找到他
this guy is a gun for hire, so we find him,
就能找到雇主
we're gonna find whoever put him up to this.
-这就去  保持联系  -好的
- On it. Keep you posted. - Okay.
会解决的
It's gonna be fine.
我知道
I know it is.
我跟许多出色的人共事过
I've worked with the best,
你比他们任何人都强
and you'd run circles around any of them
更别提在你喝了第一杯咖啡之后了
before your first cup of coffee.
有你保护  我十分安心
I feel completely safe in your care.
你才认识我两天
After knowing me for just two days?
不  我认识你两分钟后就知道了
No, after knowing you for two minutes.
所以你觉得很了解我了吗
So you think you got me figured out, huh?
除了一件事
Except for one thing.
你和卡塞尔是不是
Are you and Castle...
是
Yes.
是认真的吗
Is it serious?
是  可以说是吧
Yes. Yeah, you could say it's serious.
但事实上  你也不确定
But the truth is, you don't really know.
否则  你就不会犹豫了
Otherwise, you wouldn't have hesitated.
没有  只是
No, it's just, uh...
我们从没认真地谈过  仅此而已
We've never really talked about it. That's all.
为什么
Why not?
就是没有
We just haven't.
那他就是个傻瓜
Then he's a fool.
不  是
No, it's, uh...
只是  很复杂
It's just, it's--it's complicated.
凯特
Kate,
遇见你这样的女人后就该知道怎么做
There's nothing complicated about meeting a woman like you
根本就没有复杂一说
and knowing what to do.
不
No.
卧倒
aah! Get down!
贝克特
Hey, Beckett.
卡塞尔  我没事
Hey, Castle. I'm fine.
好
Okay.
-那就好  -谢谢  警监
- All right. - Thanks, Captain.
沃恩已经回到警局了
Vaughn's already back at the precinct.
在找到安全处所之前  盖茨想留他在那里
Gates wants to keep him there until we find a new safe house.
是啊  那里起码没有
Yeah, preferably one without windows
狙击手能射透的窗户
that snipers can shoot through.
看起来是从街对面的酒店里开的枪
It looks like the shot came from the hotel across the street.
警察们在搜寻巴伯  目前还没找到
Uniforms are canvassing for Barber, but so far, nothing.
我不太明白
I don't understand.
他怎么知道你和沃恩在这里
How did he even know you and Vaughn were here?
可能从沃恩从餐厅那次里逃脱之后
Well, maybe he's been watching us
他就一直在监视我们
since Vaughn survived the attempt at the restaurant.
贝克特  虽然我也不想
Hey, Beckett. I hate to do this to you,
但是我需要录你的口供
But I need to take your statement.
没事的
No, that's fine.
好的  第一枪的时候你站哪
All right, uh, where were you standing when first shot come?
我在
I was...
这里
right over here.
好的
Okay, and, um,
沃恩在哪里
Where was Vaughn?
这里
Right there.
好的  这里
Right, uh... Here?
他为什么站得这么近
Why was he standing so close?
我就不懂了  这不就
I don't understand. That would...
等一下  要是他站这里的话
Wait a minute. If he was standing there...
那么子弹就会
then the bullet would've gone
直接穿过他的头
right through his head.
巴伯怎么会射偏呢
How did Barber miss?
在第一枪前  沃恩绊了一跤
Well, before the first shot, Vaughn stumbled.
绊了一跤
Stumbled?
他既不是小孩又不是老人怎么会站不稳呢
Kids and old people stumble. How did he stumble?
我也不知道  他就是绊了一跤
I don't know. He just did.
所以说他先是吃错了菜
So he ate the wrong entree
没被毒死
and avoided being poisoned,
然后又时机刚好的绊了一跤
And then he stumbled at just the right moment
躲过了刺客穿过玻璃的子弹
to avoid being shot by an assassin through a window.
没人能这么幸运
Nobody's that lucky.
到底怎么回事  凯特
What's going on here, kate?
他吻了我  好了吧  卡塞尔
He kissed me. Okay, Castle?
他干什么了
He what?
我觉得我该消失了
I think I have all I need here.
听着  我没打算对你撒谎
Look, I'm not gonna lie to you.
我们正在谈论你
We were talking about you,
正在谈论感情
we were talking about relationships,
然后他就吻了我
and then he kissed me.
但这并不代表什么
But it didn't mean anything,
起码对我来说不代表什么
at least not to me.
好吧  他亲了你
Well, if he kissed you,
你为什么就不把他推开呢
why wouldn't you just push him away?
这刚好
Which is...
是他还活着的原因
why he's not dead.
街对面酒店的前台
The front desk clerk from the hotel across the street
认出了托马斯·巴伯
positively identified Thomas Barber.
说他用假名入住了那里
Said he was staying under an assumed name.
找到他了吗
Any sign of him?
没有  但是他房间的电话记录
No, but the phone records from his room
显示他给一个号码打了好几次电话
show that he made several calls to a single number.
你绝对猜不到他打给谁了
You'll never guess who Barber was calling.
帕拉蒂小姐
Ms. Paralti,
从你上次来这里之后
Some additional information has come to light
我们又有了新的信息
since you were last here.
比如说你爸爸
Like the fact that your father
曾经财政紧张
was in financial dire straights
欠了七万五千美元
to the tune of $75,000.
他差点丢了家族农场  但是突然之间
He nearly lost the family farm, and then suddenly...
他保住了
He didn't.
这件事又有什么关系
What does that have to do with anything?
这或许能解释
Well, it may explain
你为什么做了平时不会做的事情
why you did something you otherwise wouldn't.
比如说用致命剂量的神经毒素
Like turn over a lethal dose of neurotoxin
来换钱偿还欠款
in exchange for the money to pay off that debt.
我不懂你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
这是什么
What's this?
托马斯·巴伯的电话记录
The records of phone calls made by Thomas Barber,
他是名职业杀手
a contract killer.
这是他给你打的电话
Phone calls that he made to you.
听着  求你们了
Look, please, I...
我不知道他打算害人的
I didn't know he was gonna hurt anyone.
他说自己是竞争对手的人
He told me he was from a rival lab,
他们想先获得专利
that they wanted the patent first.
我很生埃里克的气
I was mad at Eric, a--
我也需要钱
and I needed the money.
-你们在哪里见面  -我们没见过
- Where did you meet? - We didn't.
我们打电话
We talked on the phone,
然后我把药放在事先约好的地方
and I dropped the vial at a prearranged place.
你是怎么拿钱的
How did you get paid?
他告诉我去开一个离岸账户
He told me to set up an offshore account.
在我送完药后  钱就汇来了
The day after the drop, the money just appeared.
伙计们  看看
Hey, guys, check it out.
钱是通过银行汇款到户的
The money arrived via a wire transfer.
有了辛迪的配合
With Cindy's cooperation,
我们追踪到了一个墨西哥能源公司
we were able to track it to a Mexican energy company
名叫墨日能源
called Mexisolar.
我听埃里克谈起过这个公司
I heard Eric talk about this.
这个墨西哥太阳能公司和埃里克·沃恩有何关系
What does a Mexican solar company have to do with Eric Vaughn?
公司是他的
He owns it.
事实上  亚瑟·菲尔德被毒害的当晚
In fact, the night that Arthur Felder was poisoned,
他和埃里克·沃恩安排去参观公司
He and Eric Vaughn were arranging a site visit to the company
因为菲尔德想要翻倍他的投资
because Felder wanted to double-up his investment.
所以无论发生什么事
So whatever's going on,
都是和公司有关的
it has to involve this company.
是  但是贝克特  还有呢
Yeah, but, Beckett, there's more.
授权汇款到辛迪账户的人
The person who authorized the wire transfer
就是埃里克·沃恩
into Cindy's account was Eric vaughn.
似乎他就是幕后指使
It looks like he's behind this whole thing.
这不可能
That can't be right.
我刚刚和提华纳的顾问通过电话
Yo. I just got off the phone with the consulate in Tijuana.
这个公司 墨日能源
This company--Mexisolar--
根本就不存在
It doesn't exist.
他们几个月前就关闭了墨西卡利的工厂
They shut down the factory in Mexicali months ago.
什么  这说不通
What? This is making no sense.
正相反  我的朋友们
Au contraire, my friends.
这案子头一回合情合理了
For the first time, this is making perfect sense.
墨日能源
Mexisolar...
是个骗局
is a scam.
埃里克·沃恩在利用它欺诈投资者
Eric Vaughn's been using it to fleece his investors.
卡塞尔  沃恩身价十亿美元
Castle, Vaughn is worth a billion dollars.
他不会诈骗的
He's not gonna be running scams.
贝克特
Oh, Beckett.
当年他们也是这么说伯尼·麦道夫的
That's what they said about Bernie Madoff.
跟麦道夫一样  很可能
And like madoff, it's quite possible
沃恩的整个帝国都是空中阁楼
Vaughn's entire empire is a house of cards.
如果菲尔德要去墨日能源工厂参观
If Felder was going to visit the Mexisolar factory,
他就会发现这个骗局
he'd have found out about the scam.
空中阁楼就会土崩瓦解
The house of cards would collapse.
这埃里克·沃恩不能接受
Eric Vaughn couldn't have that.
而要逍遥法外  有什么法子会比
And what better way to get away with murder
让自己看来就是袭击目标更好的呢
Than by making yourself look to be the intended target?
你们难道不明白吗
Don't you see?
这整件事就是个谜中谜
This entire thing is a charade.
他就是我们的凶手
He's our killer.
他耍了我们
He played us.
主要是你
Well, mostly you.
听了这么多年招供
Of all the confessions over all the years,
这一次的
this one...
会在我心里留下特殊的位置
is going to hold a special place in my heart.
卡塞尔  我打算自己
Castle, I'm going in there...
进去
Alone.
但我们是个团队
But we're a team,
而且我迫切地需要看着他崩溃
and the universe demands that I see him crumble.
不  招供是要把沃恩绳之以法
No, this one has to be about putting Vaughn away
其他无关紧要
and nothing else.
别担心  他会崩溃的
And don't worry. He will crumble.
把百叶窗开着
Leave the blinds open.
我不知道我该对哪件事更不安
I'm not sure which I should be more disturbed about,
是有人想要对我一枪爆头
that someone tried to shoot my head off
还是我试图亲你的时候  你推开了我
or that you pushed me away when I kissed you.
我们谈谈吧
Uh, yeah, let's-- let's talk about that,
谈谈你生命中的那些企图
about these attempts on your life,
谈谈墨日能源
about Mexisolar.
-墨日能源  -你的公司
- Mexisolar? - Your company.
那家并不存在的公司
The one that doesn't exist.
它当然存在
Of course it exists.
否则我会知道的  我创办了它
I should know, I founded it
投资了数百万
and invested millions.
对  亚瑟·菲尔德也是
Right, so did Arthur Felder.
准确地说是三千万美元
$30 million, to be exact.
现在都一去不返了
And now it's all gone.
这是什么  玩笑吗
What is this, a joke?
这不是玩笑  这就是墨日能源
It's not a joke. That's Mexisolar.
不不  这太疯狂了
No, no, this is crazy.
这家公司没有赤字
The company's completely solvent.
我们的工厂是最先进的
Our factory is state-of-the-art.
我看过现金流报告  签订的合同
I've seen cash flow reports, signed contracts.
你是说这些吗
You mean like these?
它们是伪造的
They're fraudulent.
这不可能
That's not possible.
这怎么不可能  都是你签了字的
How is it not possible? You signed them.
我的员工每天要让我签几十份文件
Look, my staff give me dozens of documents to sign every day.
-可这是你的公司  -对
- It's your company. - Yes.
但我不会每天核查
But I don't oversee the day to day.
那谁会
Then who does?
故事很精彩  警探
That is quite a story, detective.
确实  具备一切精彩的元素
Oh, it is. It's got everything--
盗窃  背叛  谋杀
Larceny, betrayal, murder,
还有你  通过墨日能源劫走数百万
And you looting millions from mexisolar.
而你都让埃里克·沃恩签署所有的报告
But since you had Eric Vaughn signing off on all of the reports,
所以没有人会严格审查这家公司
no one took a hard look at the company.
直到亚瑟·菲尔德想知道他的钱都用在哪了
Until Arthur Felder wanted to see where his money was going.
而你不能让这种事发生  对吗
And you couldn't have that, could you?
你们认为我杀了亚瑟·菲尔德
Uh, you think I killed Arthur Felder?
是的  但你想杀死的人是沃恩
Yes, but it was Vaughn that you wanted dead.
你知道那些文件记录会让这看上去像是
You knew that the paper trail would make it look like
他从公司贪污了钱
he had embezzled money from the company.
所以你雇了杀手
So you hired a hit man,
只不过他杀错了人
except he killed the wrong guy. Oops.
你们口说无凭
You have no proof of any of this.
别这么肯定
Don't be so sure.
给辛迪·帕拉蒂转钱的那家银行
The bank that transferred the money to Cindy Paralti
截获了IP地址
captured an I.P. Address,
他们追踪到了你的电脑
and they traced it back to your computer.
结束了  大卫
It's over, David.
我没有偷那笔钱
Look, I didn't steal that money.
我只是拿它下了注  可运气不佳
I just made some bets with it that underperformed.
我拿了新墨日能源的资金  增加了一倍投入
I-I-I took the new Mexisolar funding, and I doubled down.
要是埃里克  也会这么做的
I mean, that's what Eric would have done.
该死
Damn it.
这个娄子越捅越大
The hole just getting deeper and deeper.
事情一经败露  就意味着坐牢
It all would've come out, and it would've meant prison.
我别无选择
I had no choice.
真是奇妙啊  你可以认识一个人十年
It's amazing how you can know someone for ten years
却对他们一无所知
and never really know them at all...
而有的人认识才几天
And know someone for a few days, and...
就好像已经十分熟悉
feel like you know them so well.
有件事告诉你  你会很高兴
Well, you will be happy to know
联调局抓到托马斯·巴伯
that the Feds caught Thomas Barber
试图越过加拿大边境  所以...
trying to cross the Canadian border, so...
都结束了
It's over.
我想是的
Yeah. I suppose it is.
保重  埃里克
Take care, Eric.
你也是  凯特
You, too, Kate.
要走吗
Leaving?
知道吗
You know...
那可真是一位非凡的女子
That's an extraordinary woman you have there.
我知道
I know.
你真知道吗
Do you?
有什么事  卡塞尔
What is it, Castle?
我刚躺在沙发上真的非常舒服
I was really comfortable on that couch.
是我必须要做件事
There's something I need to do,
这件事  得要你来看
Something that... You need to see.
等等
Wait.
不  我可没说
No, ca--I didn't say
永远不想让你玩游戏了
that I never want you to play your game again.
不  我知道  别担心  线我还有
No, I know. Don't worry. I have more cords.
这只是象征性的  但你说得对
This is just symbolic. But you're right.
我最近把你看做是理所应当的
I've been taking you for granted.
但以后不会了  今晚
But no longer. Tonight...
都是为了我
It's all about me.
-难道不应该是为了我吗  -不
- Shouldn't it be about me? - Nope.
因为今晚是我
'cause tonight it's all about me...
给你
giving you...
做一次浪漫的全身按摩
a romantic full-body massage.
卡塞尔
Castle.
说吧
Yeah?
我们接下来怎么办
Where are we goin'?
去卧室
To the bedroom.
来吧  你会喜欢的
Come on. You're gonna love this.